<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Katya Bondar Performance Artist</title>
    <description>Official website of the performance artist Katya Bondar. Check my announcements and last events. Contact me and let's collaborate!</description>
    <link>https://katyabondar.com</link>
    <atom:link href="https://katyabondar.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 22:30:46 +0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 22:30:46 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Мег Стюарт</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Мег Стюарт – хореограф, танцовщица и художница родилась в Новом Орлеане (США) в 1965 году. В 1983 году переехала в Нью-Йорк, где училась в Университете Нью-Йорка, а затем в центре танца и перформанса Movement Research. В настоящий момент живет и работает в Европе – в Брюсселе и Берлине.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/99716791?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ее первая полнометражная работа &lt;b&gt;Disfigure Study&lt;/b&gt; была показана на фестивале Klapstuk в Лёвене (Бельгия) в октябре 1991 года. В этой работе Стюарт представила “изуродованное” тело как нечто реально существующее и уязвимое, поддающееся деконструкции, искажению или перемещению, но при этом все еще имеющее значение и способное функционировать. 
В ее новаторской хореографии чувствовалось влияние постструктурализма, в особенности идеи Жака Дерриды, которые были довольно модными в интеллектуальных и художественных кругах того времени. Эта и ее следующая работа &lt;b&gt;No Longer Readymade&lt;/b&gt; (1993) отразили тенденцию на интеллектуализацию современного танца в Бельгии – формировании пространства художественной критики и художественной саморефлексии.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/81482778?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;В 1994 году, Мег Стюарт, вдохновленная художественной средой в Бельгии, основала в Брюсселе танцевальную компанию &lt;b&gt;Damaged Goods&lt;/b&gt;. По словам Стюарт, она хотела создать открытую, подвижную мультидисциплинарную структуру, где танцовщики были бы независимы и могли реализовывать как свои идеи, так и помогать другим. Вместе они создали уже свыше 30 работ, среди которых помимо танцевальных – инсталяции (&lt;b&gt;The Only Possible City&lt;/b&gt; (2008)), видео-арт (&lt;b&gt;the invited&lt;/b&gt; (2003), &lt;b&gt;Somewhere in between&lt;/b&gt; (2004)), сайт-специфичные проекты (&lt;b&gt;Projecting [Space[&lt;/b&gt; (2017)) и публикации (книга &lt;b&gt;Are we here yet?&lt;/b&gt; (2013)). Для каждого мультидисциплинарного проекта Стюарт пытается выработать особенный художественный язык.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Импровизация играет важную роль в творчестве Мег Стюарт. В проектах &lt;b&gt;Crash Landing&lt;/b&gt; (1996-1999), &lt;b&gt;Auf den Tisch!&lt;/b&gt; (2005-2011), &lt;b&gt;City Lights – a continuous gathering&lt;/b&gt; (2016) через импровизацию она работает с воспоминаниями и исследует физические и эмоциональные состояния.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/210529478?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Мег Стюарт регулярно ведет образовательную деятельность – проводит воркшопы и мастер-классы в танцевальных школах, на фестивалях.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;В России первый и пока единственный раз Мег Стюарт была в октябре 2019 года на фестивале Территория с работой &lt;strong&gt;Solo Meg Stuart&lt;/strong&gt; и воркшопом.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;По материалам официального сайта &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.damagedgoods.be/&quot;&gt;Damaged Goods/Meg Stuart&lt;/a&gt; и книги Rudi Laermans – Moving Together.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/meg-stuart/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/meg-stuart/</guid>
        
        <category>люди</category>
        
        
        <category>article</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Presentation of Heat and Humidity solo</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;How can you articulate a problem into a dance? How to create conditions for movement to be born? How to move in a disaster?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In my work, I examine physicality from the point of view of the political aspects of gender, queer, sexuality, historical trauma, identity. I’m interested in today issues related to the theme of thermal disaster, black holes, future, slime, hybrid space.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Katya offers a number of hashtags to her solo work:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;heat and humidity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;slowness infection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;movement attaches&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tongue = anti-current / glue&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tomorrow melts in statistical losses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sensory coma&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;constant occurrence or intense compression&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;slow-caking translation of memory into momentum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;neutralization of thermal characteristics cancels thermal guidance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Club of Anonymous Dancing is an evening of presenting new works in progress by performance artists. At meetings, the viewer is offered the practice of watching - LOVING GAZE. With the help of this practice, organizers want to create an adoption space that reveals the potential of each of the participants.
For a loving look, it doesn’t matter: do you have a description ready for work, do you concretize your statement, do you fully understand what the concept is - it’s all not important! If you find yourself in a situation of “ignorance” - be sure to come to us!
We want to get away from the conventional framework for creating work and focus on the process and collective experience on a sensual level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When: 12/28/2019, 6:00 p.m. - 9:00 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where: conference room of the Nekrasov library. (Baumanskaya St., 58/25 - 14; 5th floor)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Showing 4+ works with a maximum timing of 20 minutes + 10 minutes to discuss each work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/556979254861709&quot;&gt;Facebook Event Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/heat-and-humidity/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/heat-and-humidity/</guid>
        
        <category>work-in-progress</category>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
        
        <category>announcement</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tentacles</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;/hi//what does this body make?//&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the perspective of hyperverities, chthonic “abominations with many tentacles (polytendriled abominations)” - “Unspoken” (Unuttera) that awaits us at the end of the story, is leading the story. &lt;!--more--&gt;The tentacles of these hyperbelieving abominations extend through time, are selected to the present moment, revealing themselves as the “dark will” of progress: it breaks political cultures, destroys traditions, dissolves subjectivity.
Hypervision is a framework or channel into which everything apocalyptic flows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/people//what is this mind made of?//&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/tentacles/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/tentacles/</guid>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Extremophile Body</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An extremophile is an organism that thrives in extreme environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does our social body live today?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What it feels and requires?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does the body loose its information nowadays?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LiIDK1E4sFg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/extremophile-body/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/extremophile-body/</guid>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Schizoid Children</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Witch, monster, alien and a cyborg - each passes the line between fiction and contextual reality, stereotype and fear, oppression and powerful power at the same time. Everyone has the ability to change the form of their choice, to scare their tormentors, to find power in a strange world. &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monsters roam among us in many forms, digital, technical, visual, natural, at the same time frightening and completely familiar bodies. Mushroom-shaped monsters also introduce the concept of “plant” movement, the basic creep of rambling, which is inconvenient from the point of view of habitual perception. Fungi allow the transfer of genetic information or programs that can be saved in the event of cataclysms no longer on a planetary, but, for example, on a galactic scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do we feel in reality?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who are we creating and who is creating us?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How did information lose its body?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What does it mean to be visible?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How did the historically specific construct called man give way to another construct called the posthuman?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where are the limits of the creep mechanism, the creep stretch?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/schizoid-children/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/schizoid-children/</guid>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
        <category>intervention</category>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Friction</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Friction is a 3 day movement research workshop based on Schizoid Children conception. It has been held as preparation for &lt;a href=&quot;https://katyabondar.com/schizoid-children/&quot;&gt;public space intervention&lt;/a&gt; at the streets of Saint Petersburg, Russia.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/friction-workshop/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/friction-workshop/</guid>
        
        <category>workshop</category>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Raving Gagarin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Raving Gagarin choreography project is based on the rave history in USSR in 90-s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rave culture in the USSR was born in the period of relative freedom of the late 80s and early 90s.&lt;!--more--&gt; At this time, squats where sensitive people, artists, musicians were hanging out, creating, searching for the boundaries of new freedom, “making flights into space”, began to appear. In this atmosphere passion for techno music was born, and so, a rave phenomenon emerged. And it seems to me that raves in the USSR, especially Gagarin-Party, carried in themselves wild energy, freedom of movement, something real that can be felt without putting on words and meaning. The first rave took place on December 14, 1991, and on December 25, Gorbachev resigned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s quite interesting that with the collapse of the USSR, the rave is actually “falling apart” as the gangsters came and displace the ravers and actually the freedom. Today I think, it is impossible to plunge into the atmosphere of the first Soviet raves as for now techno-parties often go to commerce, media and consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GhbK2UW9YZQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/raving-gagarin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/raving-gagarin/</guid>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reality Is Not My Best View /Taganka/</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Augmented reality, movement sensors, UFO crash site and some techno music what else do you need? Welcome to performance without performers and theatre without actors.&lt;!--more--&gt;
Theatre version of the REALITY IS NOT MY BEST VIEW performance shown during the Shift Festival in Taganka Theatre, Moscow, Russia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BPRBR8xVCho&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/taganka-theatre-reality-is-not-my-best-view/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/taganka-theatre-reality-is-not-my-best-view/</guid>
        
        <category>theatre</category>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Body Testing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Two day workshop as preparation for the REALITY IS NOT MY BEST VIEW performance at Taganka Theatre.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/body-testing-workshop/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/body-testing-workshop/</guid>
        
        <category>workshop</category>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reality Is Not My Best View</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;(((((( (())))))) )((((((J))) ))))))))))))) )))))(((( ())))) old reality stops broadcasting the point fades pixel death (((((((( (())))) )))))()()() ())))))))((((((((( ((((((((((( (((((((((((we are sorry that the signal has been lost))))) ))))))))))))) ?00000001100&lt;!--more--&gt; 1101111(((k/virus)))()011 1100011hyperreality //technovirusattacks// infovirus?attacks?digital010 01110000010111100010 001000101001110000001100010001000101 11100010001000101001110000001100010001000/КФТВЩЬ/postmodernculturebububursting virusvirusvirus “virus” (virogenic, viroplastic, and and or, meta, or hyper-) virus\?101100100100111011100001001001.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hyper virus devours the end of the story&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/reality-is-not-my-best-view/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/reality-is-not-my-best-view/</guid>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Creep Is A Storm From Heaven</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You are falling into the dead space. You are washed by the waves of emptiness. The signal is lost.
You become vulnerable. Vulnerable means to be visible to other people. &lt;!--more--&gt;To be visible to others means to destroy yourself from the inside and outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You cannot stop what cannot be stopped.
You cannot touch without being touched.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/the-creep-is-a-storm-from-heaven/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/the-creep-is-a-storm-from-heaven/</guid>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Is A Lecture ... This Is A Queer Object</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Queer culture in 2018 finally burst out of the close community into the big world. It seems that the future lies with it - and what do we know about its past? Habitual appeals for history to museums and archives are still often struck by the marginality and unexplored queer experience, but large institutions, brave activists and attentive artists are already correcting this.&lt;!--more--&gt; The Tate of London hosts an exhibition of queer art, the Victoria and Albert Museum and the Cambridge Museum of Zoology come up with queer tours. In Russia, archives of material evidence from hate crimes are archived, in Australia - unremarkable everyday queer things, in the USA - works of queer Muslim artists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do museums change when they begin to collect queer objects?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does the fluid and elusive queer theory put up with the museum’s habit of typing everything?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And the most importantly, why do we all need our own queer museum?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/this-is-a-queer-object/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/this-is-a-queer-object/</guid>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
        <category>lecture-performance</category>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ilunga</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Urban Russian creature.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Socialization is the process of learning to behave in a way that is acceptable to society.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is it true you or is it a system crumpled you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/eiosHZxo800&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/ilunga/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/ilunga/</guid>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
        <category>intervention</category>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scotoma</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Scotoma from the Greek “darkness” — a blind area that exists in the field of view of any healthy eye, in psychology — the denial or non-recognition of any real facts, experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social exclusion, which focuses on everyday life, is reflected in the collective unconscious. The impersonal individual repeats the attempt of self-identification.&lt;!--more--&gt; The meaning of performance crystallizes at the junction of the social and material, showing the pressure of society on the individual and the average “state of mind” dictated by the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pGUifyO465c&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/scotoma/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/scotoma/</guid>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Space Of The Body</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What reminds us as a human being?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fiction, friction and ideal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/space-of-the-body/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/space-of-the-body/</guid>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Invisible Connections</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can we dance the problem of being together?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How does the sociality influence on the human personality?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lKBjr5HeYXw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://katyabondar.com/invisible-connections/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://katyabondar.com/invisible-connections/</guid>
        
        <category>performance</category>
        
        
        <category>event</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
